Okay, so now let's do the last test on section 4, which is creating CI and CI and CD pipeline.
Okay, for continuous integration, continuous development, type, line using the getLab CR, okay.
The idea here that we want to prove a code from a repository, of course, that we repository that we have here, by using the get tool.
I just want to use, for example, that is CI tool, like Jenkins, but for this tutorial, we use getLab, okay.
Just to pull the code from repositories, okay, and download the WordPress to the new directory of installation.
So, this is a pipeline to automate the two stages that we have for the lifecycle of any code, which is the deploy and build.
It will go from top down.
So, let's do this implementation together.
So, of course here you need to make sure that you have a getLab accounts, okay.
I have an account, and I will log in to it.
Okay, I am on getlab.com, I will log in.
This is my user, m_more, 87, and I have the password, I will sign in.
Okay, and I have created a project, okay, which is called, this is a group for the project, m_more, 87, dash group, and this is the name of the project.
It is the same username, but for the group, dash group, for the project, dash project.
So, if I want here to see my link, for example, okay, this is the existing repository for me, okay.
So, this is my URL for it, that I will use.
So, first let's copy or clone, I have already created a new project, it's very simple.
When you have an account on getlab, you can create a new project, and I give it the name of m_more, dash project.
You can give it any name that you wish, okay.
And set is a bit to be public, and create it, okay. Now let's copy or clone this repository to the links, how I can copy this repository by using the get comment that I have, okay.
Here is a get comment that we have used before. So, here I will type, this is my link, I will type CD, clone, okay, I will clone it, and after I clone it, I want to make sure that all of the project directory, it will make directory called m_more, I want to change directory.
Automatically, so that I can view what is created inside that directory.
So, let's do this, I need to type username, and of course password, okay, I need to make sure that
I type username password correctly, then I will come back to you because there is a problem with authentication.
Okay, I need to type the comment again, okay, the problem here, that I type
it wrong, it's m_ no more, 87, that's the username most not right, okay, so now I have switched it automatically to this project, this is the repository, I have copied the repository,
from the getlab to my device, okay, if I can type this -LA, I can view that here it contains the dot,
it's hidden file and ready, because it is empty new projects, this is the hidden file inside it, okay.
So, I have copy the repository, this is the first thing to do, now if we can use folder structure in any repository, okay, I need to set the scripts,
define this is the scripts containing the deployment, okay, and this is the ML file which contains instructions for the two stages of the deploy and build.
Okay, so I need first to make sure to set the environment to prepare it to download all the words press bytes, and then later if these succeeds, I will enter the build.
And when I enter the build, I need to execute the scripts here.
And of course, this is the word press file, which is wp-content directory, that will after I click on the automation scripts executed,
it will modify this word press content, so the first thing here, I need to create the folder structure for my file, that's why I copied it,
so that I can manage it from my Alma Linux server.
So, the first thing here, I need to create the directories, okay, including the files, this is the ML file and this is the SH, this is our two directories and this is our two file,
file of getlab-ci and the scripts, so let's do it.
Okay, here we have directories and file, okay, and if I go through
scripts, I should see the scripts in, or this is the configuration in this.
Okay, also if I go to scripts, sorry, if I go to scripts,
I can see the deploy-to SH that I have also created.
Okay, cool, sorry, I closed it by mistake.
So, let's enter directory again.
Okay, so let's proceed with our next step.
Do two things here, we create the deploy-script, okay, this is the last phase or the first phase,
and then we create the ML files, the ML files include everything, the deployment and the build.
Okay, so first let's start with the deploy-script, okay, let's edit the deploy-to SH.
So, here let's prepare that file.
It is a bash file, okay, so we set first as I have told you, it will go from top down,
so for the deployment first, before I build, I need to set the variables.
This is the service that I will use, sorry, it is user, no more, and it is a SQL server,
or database server also here, so we will use this server, and because it is the web and back end,
or a SQL server, and the deployment directory is set to home and the mobile and the build directory here is called build.
This is a directory that I will switch on to it after the deployment finishes.
Okay, and after that it should echo the deployment to the server, and I will should start to deploy all copy all of the files to the server.
So the first step is setting the variables and copy the file to the server,
and of course it will make sure that all the data files would also be deleted from the directory.
It will synchronize or copy only the files that are not deleted or exist on the directory.
And also it will do fix the permission so that as we have done before,
we need to check the permission for inside the container itself so that it can write for the WordPress on the WordPress file,
and after that it will start Docker content, and the deployment is completed.
Okay, this is an automation script, so let's copy all of this.
Okay, and save.
Okay, cool.
Now we just make it executable by typing change modification plus X scripts just to make these scripts executable.
All runable.
Okay, we need to set these comments from outside, because it invokes scripts deploy.
Scripts deploy.sh.
Okay, now we move to the next steps, step five.
Let's create now the GitLab.
This is GitLab or CI pipeline containing the YAML configuration.
So here let's open by our beautiful nano tools.
Let's open this file.
And here it is a little bit lengthy because it contains actually two stages, as I have told you, sorry, it contains first the build,
then the deploy is the last thing to do, and the build is the first thing to adjust the diversity.
So, the stage is here is to build, to build, then deploy.